Roger Shubho Madhu

111 Rue Rielle, Verdun, Montreal, QC H4G 2S4

☑ rogermadhu@gmail.com

• rogermadhu

in/roger-madhu

 \Box +1-438-722-8388

SUMMARY

Dynamic, professional, team player with large scale project development experience such as ERP, CRM, CMS, telecommunication technologies, charging gateway and more. Academic research experience with projects involving machine learning, AI and heuristics on image and text processing.

KEY SKILLS

Java, ASP.Net, C#, Python, Machine Learning, AI, Heuristics, Team Management, PHP, Javascript, Erlang, C++, MySQL, MSSQL, Data Migration, SAP, ABAP, SCRUM, TDD, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Docker, Kubernatics, AWS, Grafana, ETL pipeline, Neural Networks, Distributed Systems, Linux, Oracle.

EXPERIENCE

Jesta I.S

Montreal, QC, Canada

Programmer/Developer in Professional Services

July 2021 - Present

Technologies: Oracle, C#, Asp.Net, Java, Python, AngularJS, WPF, VB, Azure, DevOps

Artificial Intelligence Concordia, Concordia University

Montreal, QC, Canada

May 2019 - July 2019

Intern

o ConcordAI Summer 2019 Cohort

Technologies: Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, API, Machine learning, Heuristics.

Concordia University

Montreal, QC, Canada

Research Assistant

September 2018 - December 2019

Semantic analysis of text using machine learning.

b-cause Bangladesh. Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Senior Software Developer

August 2017 - April 2018

- o Manage Bangladesh office branch software development team.
- o Software development task scheduling, distribution and follow up among team.
- Requirement gathering and analysis.
- Top level system development and design.
- Database Design and development.
- API Development.
- Server services development.
- Server management and configuration.
- SSIS Data Migration.
- Other applications development.

Technologies: AngularJS, ASP.NET, C#, Javascript, JQuery, MSSQL, MySQL, SSIS, API, SOAP, JSON, GIT, Tortoise SVN, Charging Gateway.

Fair Distribution Ltd.-SAMSUNG

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Programmer

August 2015 - August 2017

- o Requirement Analysis & Feasibility Study
- System Architecture Designing
- Database Designing
- o API and Web Application Development
- Project Overview and Implementation

Technologies: Java, Spring, ASP.NET, C#, Javascript, JQuery, MSSQL, MySQL, API, SOAP, JSON, Android, SAP, ABAP.

.....

VU Mobile Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Software Engineer

January 2014 - August 2015

- Participate in all phases of web based application/software development
- Prepare product documentation
- o Design user interface
- o Bug fixing and testing
- Developing web reporting
- Other Responsibilities:
- Maintenance and monitoring of other company web based services necessary for daily operation. (DevOps) Technologies: Java, ASP.NET, C#, Webforms, Javascript, JQuery, MSSQL, API, SOAP, JSON, Bash scripting, Payment gateway, Telecommunication, GPS Tracking, Signal Triangulation, Tortoise SVN, JIRA, GIT.

Solutions360

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Asst. Manager - Marketing (International Internet Gateway)

January 2013 - July 2013

- Market Research
- Feasibility analysis of infrastructure
- Creating Documentation and proposals
- Analyzing financial quotations

EDUCATION

Concordia University

Master of Applied Computer Science

Montreal, QC, Canada May 2018 - December 2020

American International University-Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh May 2008 - December 2012

Academic Projects & Research.....

- Machine Learning Dataset construction and feature extraction, Modified MNIST, Semi-Amortized Variational Autoencoders.
- o Distributed Systems ETL pipeline processing using Docker, AWS, Kubernatics, Webcrawler.
- o Artificial Intelligence Game state-space searching using heuristics in python.
- o Natural Language processing Project using Bag of words model, Stanford Parser, NLTK.
- o Information Retrieval Created webcrawler with parser, dynamically create dictionaries, store the dictionaries with the blocks, integrate sorting and merging on large datasets.

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- o Concordia Merit Scholarship 2018
- o BCS Computer Gaming Contest 2004, 1st Prize